PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative and vision-driven Technical Writer for enterprise software with 3+ years of experience developing effective documentation and online content solutions for tech products. Specialties include SaaS documentation, online help, cybersecurity, structured authoring, docs-as-code, and web accessibility.

Skills and Tools: DITA, XML, oXygen, Git, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Office 365 Suite, Google Workspace, Notepad++, Snagit, Markdown, HTML5, CSS3, VS Code, reStructuredText, Docs-as-Code, Agile Environment, DevOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RIVERACES CORPORATION (CONTRACT), CHATTANOOGA, TN, JULY 2023 TO PRESENT

TECHNICAL WRITER/DOCUMENTATION MANAGER

- Build comprehensive user and admin product documentation for OpenPTC's new enterprise Positive Train Control software, leveraging docs-as-code infrastructure with Sphinx and Read the Docs
- Coordinate and manage the documentation site through our GitHub source code repository and Read the Docs Admin, ensuring seamless version control and efficient collaboration among team members
- Define and execute the documentation strategy, aiming to optimize the user experience by providing clear, concise, and user-friendly documentation that empowers customers to use the software with ease

TREND MICRO, TAIPEI, TAIWAN, JULY 2022 TO JULY 2023

TECHNICAL WRITER/UX WRITER

- Wrote, maintained, and published Online Help documentation for a diverse range of enterprise cybersecurity XDR SaaS apps and features including Zero Trust Secure Access, Mobile Security, Email Security, Network Security, Risk Insights, Threat Intelligence, Point Product Connections, Service Gateway, and others
- Interviewed and liaised with developers, UI designers, visual designers, and project managers to gather insights and ensure accurate and user-friendly documentation
- Applied organizational and time management skills to handle multiple projects at once while complying with rigid deadlines and software release schedules in an agile environment
- Adapted quickly to a multi-cultural, multi-lingual work environment, regularly coordinating with cross-functional teams and stakeholders across Taiwan, China, Japan, Australia, and North America

MODULAR AGENCY (FREELANCE), TAIPEI, TAIWAN, NOVEMBER 2021 TO PRESENT

WRITER AND EDITOR

- Created compelling B2B marketing and web content for leading tech companies including Microsoft, ACER, KYMCO, and BenQ, effectively promoting products and services to target audiences
- Led the research and development efforts for a comprehensive 22-page market analysis report, enabling a tech company's successful entry into the Taiwan market and providing valuable industry-specific insights
- Produced and edited a materials including web copy, case studies, market analyses, long-form blog articles, and Key Selling Points (KSPs), emphasizing substance, user experience, and accessibility

LIVEABC INTERACTIVE CORPORATION, TAIPEI, TAIWAN, SEPTEMBER 2021 TO FEBRUARY 2022

EDITOR

- Edited, copyedited, and proofread English language curriculum and other content for LiveABC's various publications
- Developed and edited test preparation material for TOEIC, TOEFL, vocational school, and university testing
- Partnered with cross-functional departments, engaging in collaborative revision processes

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

BACHELOR OF ARTS (B.A.) IN ENGLISH RHETORIC AND PROFESSIONAL WRITING, 2020 University of Tennessee, TN

MANDARIN COURSEWORK, DECEMBER 2021 TO FEBRUARY 2022

Mandarin Training Center at National Taiwan Normal University

CERTIFICATE IN EDITING, FEBRUARY 2022

Poynter Institute